Hello?
Hello.
Okay, this is a continuation of the recordings.
I think I don't need to do this greeting each time
because we are going to concatenate everything together.
But bear with me.
Um, Now we have okay, now.
We will go to the config file and the n exemplifies.
So let's go through this bit by bit.
We are using a library called FastAPI.
Okay?
REST framework, okay.
web framework and to receive the requests from the front end ui.
Okay?
So, FastAPI has a lot of documentation and I suggest
seeing the main the main the official docs for it.
Official documentation for it.
It's really it's what is this?
Yeah, sorry.
It's really clean and I liked it.
And it's weird for someone to say that he likes
documentation and that he's having fun reading documentation.
But really the, the team there did a
fantastic job at documenting how it works.
And one of its features is uh, settings and uh,
settings here is is a class that is responsible
for taking different values from different places.
What do I mean by this?
Let me explain with an example.
We can run the server, the FastAPI server by running
a command here and then passing arguments, for example
an argument called debug mode and give it values.
Okay?
Now.
This is one place where we can get like
you, you, you wanna say it constant?
Okay.
You can say environment variables.
You can say like just configuration settings.
Okay.
Like configuration setting.
This is one place to get them.
Okay.
From the command line.
Terminal arguments.
Okay.
So this is this is what this means.
And you can get it as well from, other places.
Let me show you an example that you're probably familiar with.
The end file.
I'm showing you an example of it.
So you can here set the keys that you want to be
read in the environment while the code is running.
So again, you see the bug mode here.
Okay?
So this is another place.
So there are multiple places.
I'm not going to explain all of them.
What we are interested in understanding is.
That there, there is precedence.
Precedence, meaning that if I set this here
and then set this in the n exemp file this will
take precedence over the n for example, file.
So meaning more priority, this will be prioritized.
Okay?
So this is another thing to take in mind.
What you need to understand from, from all of these
is that what we're currently using is the following.
We are using .env file.
.env file.
So we're loading the values from here,
from there into, into this class.
So you're going to see here a lot of keys.
Okay?
These keys, most of them are loaded from the dot end, for example.
So here you'll see debug mode.
Okay?
So debug mode here.
I, I got that from the digital example.
Okay.
It, this is done automatically.
So when you just run the script in main, a P point and, and the,
and the, and the Fast API server like runs in the background
and it and it sees this base settings from the identical class.
It runs that as well.
You see that, we see that it checks, it checks for these values.
So it see that, okay, debug mode and sees based
on the list above, where can I find this value.
And it goes through this list and it finds it in .env file
because it reads in the I think we, we passed it here.
Yeah.
The in file when we, we con fill it, settings,
config, we, we specified that it is found in here.
And this is respective to the root.
So that's why we put the file in the root.
The root file here will be in the root.
Okay?
So again, adult file is literally the same as
this, but with the actual values, secret values.
So it'll be similar to this, but it'll not have this export.
Okay.
So what does this export do?
Basically, there is another option.
This is option info.
You can you can run this as a script, okay.
In the terminal.
To, to take line by line as a command and run that.
So this is a command in Bash saying, export this key.
So it'll export this key to the environment
variables of the environment, okay?
That's currently running.
So if you decide to go with that path,
then you will be abiding by this rule.
Which one?
This rule?
The environment variables rule.
Okay.
So these are general environment variables that's available
and how can you see them while the code is running?
You can do something like this import os and then os environ.
This will be a dictionary, I believe.
Yes.
Containing all of the environments currently based.
So so, so, so.
Suppo, assuming that you decide to go with that other
path of running this script, this best script, and
running these commands one by one in the terminal.
Then you should see when you, when you run this, when, when
you print this, you should see normal environment variables
that are always there when you run any Python script.
And you should see as well the custom keys that you inserted here.
Okay?
So but we don't, we will not go through
that with that path, and instead.
Or I personally instead just take the
stuff here and put it in a dotenv file.
And when I do that, I remove the, the export because
in the dot file, you don't need the export prefix.
So and I believe you can put some anything on the side here.
So this, this is taken as well in the
normal dotenv file when it's read.
So it, it'll take this as a key and then
what is after the equal will be taken.
Okay.
That's what I understand.
I'm not sure if this is correct though or not
because I, I, I think I faced this issue before.
So you can put comments on the side like this here.
In the actual end file you have to put it if you are going to put
it, put it on top of it or below it, don't put it to the side.
Okay?
And another thing, this is this string is optional.
So for example, for example, when I say here
two, I can also, I can also write it at, at like
this, and it'll be read as a string as well.
Okay.
So, but we, we, we put it for clarity.
Because everything here, I, if I remember
correctly, is initially read as a string.
Okay?
So if you just use the grow traditional method of of,
from NV library, import load nv, and then you load n you
will see that and then you try to, to call, for example.
And then you try to call is the get good get in the bug mode.
It, this will return true string.
Like even if you put this as a true
without the, without the double strings.
Okay?
Even if you do it like this and you, and you
print this, it'll still be decoded as a string.
It'll still appear as a string because that's how it
internalizes the, the, the, the file, how this file gets read.
So this is something for you to, to, to,
so this is, it will be a string as well.
This one will be a string.
And then you, you can do, if you are going to get
this here, for example, you won, you won't need that.
But this just a for you to understand
and you get that as a variable.
Inval.
This will actually not be an inval.
This will be a, this will be a string.
And you'll have to do something like this to
convert it to a, an same thing with debug mode,
debug mode it'll return a string was true in it.
And then I think, I think if you, if you, if you
put this and, and here a string was true, it'll
be a true value, but I'm not sure about this.
I'm, yeah, I'm not sure.
Yeah.
No, it doesn't do that.
So apologies for this.
I thought it would apply the same logic, but apparently not.
But you get the idea.
Okay, so so this is something for you to be aware of.
Of how to get environment variables at
or configurations into the environment.
Okay.
If you want a description of what the use of each
configuration here is, then there are two approaches.
First, approach growth, control, shift F global searching here.
So for example, in here I can control shift
F and I can see what it got mentioned.
It got mentioned in, in all of these for example, let
me see here, main, so if we're in debug mode right now.
And this file is the main entry point.
Then we will run the UV server, et cetera.
So you can see the importance of each code, but not
all of the configurations here can be control shift.
If, for example, if we see the open I key and
we control shift, if that, you will see that
it isn't written explicitly in any other file.
Exclude over cd, GitHub action file.
It's not written in other files.
Okay?
So this is a problem because it'll make it.
Little bit more difficult to reduce its usage, but here
we can actually rely on the comments in the example.
Okay.
I, I try to, to put the comments rating how it gets used.
Obviously open I is a clear example.
Then, you know from the name that we are using
an LLM provider, which relies on open AI model.
So we use that key.
So this makes sense.
Okay.
But other things that really don't, don't make that much sense.
I I have comments like, for example, WhatsApp.
Keys here.
I have comments for that.
Okay.
And et cetera.
And there is a tricky note regarding
the OpenAI API key specifically.
I will, I'll get back to this when I explain later files.
So yeah, this is the part of configuration.
The, the remaining of the remainder of the code.
Here is just the default values that we put.
So if you remember here, there is a
precedence on how we take each, value.
Like if we have debug mode in here and in
the .env, we will, we'll prioritize this one.
So the last thing we'll prioritize.
Prioritize is a default field value in the
sittings model, which is something like that.
If we go back to debug model, debug mode, I mean you will
see the default value that means the following if we do not
have this variable called debug mode, all capital letters,
if we don't have that passed in arguments over here.
Or exported the via the export command From the example or in
file or in, in the remaining of the above, like five settings.
If you don't have all of that, then this
will be set to as a default value over here.
Okay.
Which is false.
Yeah.
So I believe, if I remember in the live environment that we
have in, in Heroku, we, we, we don't even specify that key.
Like that envi, that key in the environment over there, over hero.
So since it doesn't exist there it'll default to false.
Okay.
And so we, we won't be in debug mode in life.
And that makes sense.
Okay.
So this is something same same as logging level.
Logging level deal.
I believe in life we don't have this mentioned.
I think so it defaults to info, which makes sense, not debugging.
What else?
I wanna say, I think this is everything related to
to config feel very, this is when we, when we when
we want to get the key called origins specifically,
which is this one which is this one this function.
Make sure that we obtain it in a specific
format, which is a, which is a list.
Okay.
So it's, it basically says the following, if we have origins.
As a string, then convert list, but it's a list.
Then leave it as is.
For example, if you go back to end example here,
you will see that origins is written as a string
and between each link and the other is a comma.
You see a coma like this.
Okay?
So this is a string, so.
This function basically tells us the following.
When this script runs and we check for Origins
and we check it in any place like the terminal or
the en file or et cetera, we do this validation.
Okay?
And if it's so it's the thing, like the one that I just showed
you, then you should strip by the this split by this this com.
Okay, otherwise you leave it as is.
There is all, I think it's pretty obvious this
function is where we instantiate that sitting
class sitting class that has all the keys above.
And we call that function everywhere basically.
So this function turns out instance of the savings
clause, and we use that literally everywhere.
Literally the sort of each file, for example, or not the sort
of, yeah, when we initialize data, the database clause or the,
an sorry agent itself, we pass it, pass it to the initials.
So it takes the settings as an initial.
So we, we, we use it a lot.
So just understanding this logic will help you out.
So this was recording the config part and yes.
Regarding now what do we have here?
Regarding, so yeah, this is a config by and and example.
Okay, I'll, I'll just take a small break
and continue the rest of the files.
One second,
what I wanna do, 9 1 2.
In the main presenter.